Ben Parisot

503-719-3537 me@benparisot.com linkedin.com/in/benparisot/ https://github.com/benparisot

I'm a full-stack JavaScript engineer and former technical producer with experience building intuitive, user-focused applications with back- and front-end web technologies and managing both external stakeholders and internal development teams.

I've worked in the tech industry since 2008 and have been working in JavaScript since 2017. I graduated from Alchemy Code Lab in Portland in the spring of 2019 with over 800 hours of intensive full-stack JavaScript training focused on the MERN stack. I am currently working in the Alchemy App Lab program as Lead Developer, managing the 5-person development team and contributing to two of the three current project code bases.

I started my career in tech as an SEO copywriter before moving into digital marketing, web production, technical project manager, and full-stack development. As a web producer I took clients through the entire lifecycle of a website project, from UX/UI design to messaging to development and deployment. As a tech producer I was responsible for prioritizing app features with clients and producers, running sprints with developers, troubleshooting apps with QA, and delivering stand-alone features early and often. I've produced AR and VR apps for Kaiser Permanente and Medtronic, touchscreen and gesture-based applications for State Farm, and have been technical producer on various projects for Cartoon Network, Visa, Fast Company, HBO, ACOG, Cigna Health, Under Armour, Oracle, and others.

In addition to my development and management skills, I also have experience building interactive art installations using generative design and projection mapping tools like TouchDesigner, Resolume, and MadMapper.

TECH

JavaScript/JSX

Express

Jest/Enzyme/Q-Unit

• HTML/CSS/Sass

• TDD

• MongoDB/Firebase

Node.is

Webpack

• Travis/Jenkins

• React/Redux

TOOLS

• Git/Github

AWS

• Illustrator

• Netlify

• Jira/Confluence

After Effects

Heroku

Basecamp

InDesign

EXPERIENCE

Lead Developer | Alchemy Code Lab | Sept 2019 - Present

As Lead Developer in Alchemy's App Lab program I am responsible for managing development teams across multiple client projects, performing code reviews with developers, approving and merging pull requests, architecting and building out new features, and resolving issues and bugs from the QA backlog. Current projects use ReactJS, Redux, React Router, Node.js, Express, Webpack, Cordova, TravisCI, Babel, Firebase, and Heroku, as well as HTML5, CSS3, Sass, and vanilla JavaScript. Current projects include:

- A mobile-first hybridized redesign of an existing Chinese language education web application.
- A suite of mobile applications to connect independent caregivers with clients that need tasks completed.
- A social media app for sharing user-generate media reviews of businesses, locations, and experiences.

Front-End Developer | $\underline{\text{LosAngeleno.com}}$ | August 2019 - Present

In my role as freelance front-end developer for LA-based arts and entertainment magazine Los Angeleno I am responsible for maintaining the Wordpress theme the site runs on, making updates to the look and behavior of site components, and squashing bugs. I work mainly in HTML and CSS.

Tech Producer | Helios Interactive, a Freeman Company | July 2016 - Jan 2019

As Tech Producer at Helios I worked with clients, producers, designers, and developers to keep projects on schedule and deliver working apps under strict deadlines. Part scrum master and part release manager, my role included architecting apps with developers, running sprints with project team members, identifying and prioritizing bugs with QA, and handling onsite and app store deployment with our ops team. I directly produced or was technical producer on such projects as:

 An augmented reality app for Medtronic that supplemented their printed marketing collateral and allowed spokespeople to capture leads at large events at scale.

- A virtual reality facility tour for Kaiser Permanente that allowed account managers to show off Kaiser's state-of-the-art facilities at events and during in-house discussions with companies searching for new insurance providers.
- An augmented reality shoot-em-up game for Cartoon Network to promote the release of the new season of Ben 10, one of their most popular and longest running programs.
- Multiple touchscreen applications for State Farm that allowed brand ambassadors to attract more people into their event footprint, generate leads via email collection, and track social engagement with the brand via customized event-specific digital takeaways.
- A large-scale touchscreen activation for Fast Company that allowed guests to pick trending items from a dynamic marketplace, add them to a wish list, and then email their wish list to themselves and others.

Digital Director | Roger That Agency | Nov 2014 - June 2016

As Digital Director at Roger That I was responsible for sourcing and managing developers for clients' web projects, launching websites after development was complete, and maintaining site themes post-launch. After deployment I would make presentational changes to the look and behavior of site components as well as help clients with email setup, domain transfers, and other technical issues.

Owner/Founder | Foster Digital Marketing | Sept 2010 - Sept 2014

As a freelance digital marketer and web producer I was responsible for taking clients through the lifecycle of a web development project, from key messaging to UX and design through development, QA, and deployment. I also performed SEO site audits on existing websites to help companies' sites perform better in search results, implemented and managed social media and PPC campaigns, and wrote blog posts, articles, and website copy.

Social Media Manager | Pink Martini/Heinz Records | May 2013 - Sept 2014

As Social Media Manager at Pink Martini, I was responsible for managing the social media accounts for Pink Martini and Heinz Records, including planning and executing digital giveaways, writing and distributing blog content, and making HTML/CSS updates to their website.

Copywriter | Mad Fish Digital | May 2008 - May 2011

As a copywriter at Mad Fish, I was responsible for writing and styling posts for a variety of B2C and B2B blogs using HTML and CSS.

FEATURED SIDE PROJECTS

Mega Nap | Node.js, React/Redux, HTML, CSS, MongoDB

A full-stack web app that allows front end developers to input data and generate RESTful API endpoints for use in their own applications.

GitHub Repo Here | Live Demo Here

Robot Haikubot | Node.js, Express, MongoDB

A Twitter bot that sends a randomly-generated haiku to those that ask for one!

GitHub Repo Here | Twitter Account Here

The News! | Vanilla JavaScript, HTML, CSS

A news search website that retrieves news articles relevant to a user's search from NewsAPI.org and paginates the results.

GitHub Repo Here | Live Demo Here

NASA Database Search | Vanilla JavaScript, HTML, CSS

A site that allows users to search the NASA GeneLab program for experiments and studies relevant to entered search words or phrases. Uses the NASA GeneLab API and paginates results.

GitHub Repo Here | Live Demo Here

Talk Giphy to Me Vanilla JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Firebase A gif translation and guessing game for gif-lovers of all ages.

GitHub Repo Here | Live Demo Here

EDUCATION

- Pacific Northwest College of Art | Currently enrolled in the PNCA Continuing Education Certification Program in graphic design
- Alchemy Code Lab | 800+ hours full-stack JavaScript training
- Willamette University | B.A. English